[{"question":"Infectious proteins are present in:","a":"Satellite viruses","b":"Gemini viruses","c":"Prions","d":"Viroids","hint":"undefined","correct":"c"},{"question":"Robert Koch's postulates to establish a micro- organism as pathogen can be obtained, after his work on:","a":"Hydrophobia","b":"Anthrax","c":"Smallpox","d":"Diphtheria","hint":"","correct":"b"},{"question":"RBC counting is low in anaemia and:","a":"Typhoid","b":"Leukemia","c":"Influenza","d":"Myxoedema","hint":"In leukemia the number of WBCs (especially granulocytes) increases but the number of RBCs decreases.","correct":"b"},{"question":"A child is suffering from Kwashiorkor, and if this child is compared with other marasmus children then what additional symptoms are present in Kwashiorkor child?","a":"Decrease in body weight","b":"Wasted muscles","c":"Oedema","d":"Impaired physical growth","hint":"","correct":"a"},{"question":"Chronic anaemia and multiple sclerosis are:","a":"Allergic diseases","b":"Hormonal diseases","c":"Autoimmunity diseases","d":"Hereditary diseases","hint":"","correct":"c"},{"question":"Vaccines are:","a":"treated bacteria or viruses or one of their proteins.","b":"MHC (major histocompatibility complex) proteins.","c":"curative medicines.","d":"monoclonal antibodies.","hint":"Vaccine contains dead, attenuated form or antigen of a pathogen which can be injected to provide immunity towards that pathogen. Monoclonal antibodies are homogenous immunological reagents of defined specificity, so that these can be utilised for diagnosis and screening with certainty.","correct":"a"},{"question":"For which of the following disease, there is preventive vaccine?","a":"AIDS","b":"Hepatitis B","c":"Syphilis","d":"Gonorrhoea","hint":"Hepatitis is a viral disease; two subgroups are hepatitis type A virus (HAV) and hepatitis type B virus (HBV). HBV causes serum hepatitis, it is most frequently transmitted by blood, products of blood. or blood contaminated instruments. Since only adults are susceptible to HBV, but vaccines are available. While children and young adults are susceptible to HAV, no vaccines are available.","correct":"b"},{"question":"Which one of the following statements is correct about T-lymphocytes in mammals?","a":"These are produced in thyroid.","b":"There are three main types- cytotoxic T-cells, helper T-cells and suppressor T-cells.","c":"These are originated in lymphoid tissues.","d":"They scavenge damaged cells and cellular debris.","hint":"The lymphocytes which differentiate in the thymus are known as the T-lymphocytes. These are responsible for the cellular immune response.","correct":"c"},{"question":"Active immunity is:","a":"borrowed from an active disease case.","b":"developed in direct response to a disease agent.","c":"the product of borrowed antibodies.","d":"passive immunity that is activated.","hint":"Active immunity is the immunity which result from the production of antibodies by the immune system in response to the presence of an antigen.","correct":"b"},{"question":"In the cell-mediated immune response, T-lymphocytes divide and secrete:","a":"Antigens","b":"Plasmogens","c":"Collagens","d":"Cytokines","hint":"T-lymphocytes perform several immune functions including the release of cytokines. Cytokines (such as interleukin or interferon) has a specific effect on the interactions between cells, or communications between cells or on the behaviour of cell.","correct":"d"},{"question":"B-lymphocytes are primarily involved in:","a":"Humoral immunity","b":"Autoimmune disorders","c":"Graft rejection","d":"Cell-mediated immunity","hint":"B-lymphocytes are involved in humoral immunity by producing antibodies.","correct":"a"},{"question":"Passive immunity is defined as immunity:","a":"Inherited from the parents.","b":"Achieved through vaccination.","c":"Acquired through first exposure to the disease.","d":"Achieved through the sera of other animals enriched in antibodies.","hint":"","correct":"d"},{"question":"If a person shows production of interferons in his body, the chances are that he has got an infection of:","a":"Typhoid","b":"Measles","c":"Tetanus","d":"Malaria","hint":"","correct":"b"},{"question":"Passive immunity is achieved from injection of","a":"Antibodies","b":"Vaccines","c":"Antigens","d":"Histamines","hint":"","correct":"a"},{"question":"Antiserum is rich in:","a":"Steroids","b":"Antibodies","c":"Antigens","d":"RBC","hint":"","correct":"b"},{"question":"Identify the disease against which human beings have innate immunity?","a":"Distemper","b":"Influenza","c":"Small-pox","d":"Rabies","hint":"","correct":"a"},{"question":"Immunoglobulin is present in sebum of:","a":"IgM","b":"IgG","c":"IgA","d":"IgE","hint":"","correct":"c"},{"question":"Lymphoid tissue is found in:","a":"Thymus","b":"Tonsils","c":"Lymph nodes","d":"All of these","hint":"","correct":"d"},{"question":"A non-infectious unnatural and unusual reaction to a substance or condition is:","a":"Toxin","b":"Allergy","c":"Infection","d":"Immunity","hint":"","correct":"b"},{"question":"A person is injected with globulin against  hepatitis. This is:","a":"Naturally acquired active immunity","b":"Naturally acquired passive immnity","c":"Artificially acquired active immunity","d":"Artificially acquired passive immunity","hint":"","correct":"c"},{"question":"The antibody dependent cytotoxicity is seen in:","a":"Local anaphylaxis","b":"Generalise anaphylaxis","c":"Immune complex reaction","d":"Non-compatable-blood transfusion","hint":"","correct":"d"},{"question":"What is released in body during disease which results in fever?","a":"Pyrogens","b":"antibodies","c":"Interferons","d":"Interleukins","hint":"","correct":"a"},{"question":"E Jenner prepared the vaccine for small pox virus using","a":"Aftemated cowpax virus","b":"Attenuated smallpox virus","c":"Large dose of smallpes virus","d":"Small dose of smallpox virus","hint":"","correct":"a"},{"question":"Monoclonal antibodies are produced from  hybrid cells, called hybridomas. The cells. employed to obtain these hybridoma cells, are","a":"B-lymphocytes and myeloma cells","b":"Lymphoma cells and hone marrow cells","c":"T-lymphocytes and myeloma cells","d":"B-lymphocytes and carcinoma cells","hint":"","correct":"a"},{"question":"Types of antibodies involved in asthma are:","a":"IgA","b":"IgM","c":"IgE","d":"IgD","hint":"IgE antibodies are involved in allergic reaction","correct":"c"},{"question":"The class of antibodies which appear first after  the infection, ix","a":"IgG","b":"IgM","c":"IgA","d":"IgD","hint":"IgM is a pentamer and has maximum (10) binding sites. IgM is the largest antibody and is the first antibody to appear in response to initial exposure to an antigen.","correct":"b"},{"question":"All allergens are non-infectious foreign substances that:","a":"increase the secretion of IgA","b":"increase the secretion of IgE","c":"increase the secretion of IgG","d":"increase the secretion of IgM","hint":"Allergens are non-infectious foreign substances that causes allergic reaction. The common allergens are dust, pollen, 45mould spores, fabrics, lipsticks,nail paints, fur, heat beacteria, etc. Allergy involves mainly the secretion of IgE antibodies and histamines. The allergy causes marked dilation of all the peripheral blood vessels.","correct":"b"},{"question":"Mast cells secrete a protein which causes the dilation of blood vassels. The protein is","a":"Pyrogen","b":"Histamine","c":"Interferon","d":"None of the above","hint":"Mast cells are large cells with densely granular cytoplasm that are found in connective tissues. Mast cell granules contain mediators of inflammation, such as histamine, serotonin, and various chemotactic factors (substances that attract white blood cells to the area of infection). Histamine released from ruptured mast cells causes marked dilation of all the arteries so that a large amount of fluid is passed from the blood to the tissues and there is a drastic fall in blood pressure.","correct":"b"},{"question":"Which one of the following conditions though harmful in itself, is also a potential saviour from a mosquito borne infectious disease?","a":"Leukemia","b":"Thalassemia","c":"Sickle cell anaemia","d":"Pemicious anaemia","hint":"A sickle cell anaemia affected person is more resistant to mosquito bom infectious disease because the sickle-cell shaped RBCs are hostile to the protozon Plasmodium","correct":"c"},{"question":"Identify the odd one out.","a":"Rabies, Influenza, AIDS","b":"Amoebiasis, Giardiasis. Trypanosomiasis","c":"Taeniasis, Ascariasis, Elephannasis","d":"Cancer, Tuberculosis, Tetamis","hint":"Rabies, influetura and AIDS are viral  discases Amoebiasin, cariasis and Irypanosomiasis are caused by protocos. Taeniasis, ascariasis and elephantiasis are the diseases caused by helminths but cancer, tuberculosis and tetanus are not related diseases. Tuberculosis and teamus are bacterial diseases while cancer is not","correct":"d"},{"question":"Encephalitis in man is a viral disease and is 39 transmitted by:","a":"Anopheles","b":"Cules","c":"Aeder","d":"Cules and deses","hint":"Rabies, influetura and AIDS are viral  discases Amoebiasin, cariasis and Irypanosomiasis are caused by protocos. Taeniasis, ascariasis and elephantiasis are the diseases caused by helminths but cancer, tuberculosis and tetanus are not related diseases. Tuberculosis and teamus are bacterial diseases while cancer is not","correct":"b"},{"question":"Aedes aegypt is a vector of","a":"Both dengue and yellow fever","b":"Dengue fever","c":"Yellow fever","d":"Japanese encephalitis","hint":"","correct":"a"},{"question":"Aedes aegypt is a vector of","a":"Both dengue and yellow fever","b":"Dengue fever","c":"Yellow fever","d":"Japanese encephalitis","hint":"","correct":"a"},{"question":"An immune disease in which the body destroys the ill-functioning of thyroid gland, is called","a":"Cretinium","b":"Myxoedema","c":"Simmond's disease","d":"Hashimoto's dise","hint":"","correct":"d"}]